

Madhan Kumar

+91 (959) 724-6797

mmpmadhan@gmail.com

LinkedIn profile: http://www.linkedin.com/in/madhan-kumar-9097bbb9

Professional working as a mechanical design engineer with more than 8+ years of experience in Semiconductor industries projects, Product Design, and pump and motor currently learning data science and automation and project leadership.

Experience

Senior Consultant

08/2022 to 04/2023

Capgemini Technologies Limited, Bengaluru, KA, INDIA

Project description: Locomotive Manufacturers-Design and make ECN for ECR,updates drawings and models, and make manufacturing assembly. Engineering Change Management (ECM) like ECO, ECR, and MCO creation.

CAD Tools: UG/NX with Team Center, Sheetmetal design, Heavy Machinery Design.

Consultant 04/2017 to 05/2022

Capgemini Technologies Limited, Coimbatore, TN, INDIA

- Creo 7.0, NX 11, AutoCAD, SolidWorks, Team center and Agile PLM
- •VBA, Python, Matlab,

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Design Support, PMI, and PLM activities to semiconductors GAS BOX and CHEM. other Subassemblies
- Mechanical routing and Gas line systems like weldment routing, Pipe, and cable routings.
- Prepare using 2D and 3D CAD software mechanical drawings, detailed drawings, and assembly models complete with calculated dimensions.
- Revise and alter detailed and layout drawings to conform to engineering changes.
- Developing Assemblies, creating a bill of materials, M&I (Machining and Inspection), Assembly and manufacturing drawing creation, and selection of OEM components.
- Gas BOX Sheet Metal Enclosure Design.
- Assembly BOM comparison, Engineering Instruction and Rework Instruction for GAS BOX.
- Engineering Change Management (ECM) like ECO, ECR, and MCO creation.
- PMI SOE Creation, 3DPDF Creation, Operational Method Sheet (OMS) Creation for ASML and LAM projects.
- To respond to the Supplier Problem Sheet (SPS) with the correct solution for the manufacturing issues.
- Preparing the team reports weekly and monthly.
- Optimize designs to address Reliability Costs, to design for Manufacturing/Assembly (DFM/DFA).
- •Design automation making 3D models using my Python programming
- Excel VBA for making excel workout

6+ years PLM and ERP: Oracle agile PLM and ERP

CAD Tools: Cero and Solid works and auto cad UG/NX with Team Center, Heavy Machinery, Jig and Fixture and Agile PLM and Kaizen making and Layout making and lean and six sigma.

Design and draftsman

10/2014 to 11/2016

Texmo industries, CBE, TN, INDIA

- Foundry engineering design and drafting pattern and core box Drawings and document Controlled Works
- CFD analyses in MAGMA software for melt flow analysis
- Updating workshop and plant layout and work flow.
- Rapid proto typing in 3d printer and 3d scanning.
- Making Kaizen and design automation using VBA
- Vendor following and Main ISO documents

CAD Tools: Solid works and auto cad, Heavy Machinery, Jig and Fixture. CFD simulation (FEA) (Magma 5.3 2016) Kaizen making and Layout making and lean and six sigma.

Language:

Tamil, English (professional),

Chinese (beginner now)

Top Skills

- CAD & 3D Modeling
- Data analysis for finding new improvements
- Creative and Development
- Project Management
- Automation Skills
- Customer support and Document support

Personal Attributes

- Time management
- Hard-working
- Creativity
- Confidence

Education and certifications

- Google Project Manager Certificate, Coursera, 2022.
- Python for Everybody Specialization Certificate, Coursera, 2022.
- ➤ IBM Data Analyst Specialization Certificate, Coursera, 2022.
- Google Data Analytics Specialization Certificate, Coursera, 2022.
- Diploma in Mechanical engineering 2014, Christ the king polytechnic college, CBE, TN, INDIA.

Documentation Work Exposure:

MS-OFFICE, Google spreadsheet, advance excel with VBA.

Mechanical Design tools:

Creo (6+ years), NX Cad with Teamcenter (2+ years), AutoCAD, SolidWorks with ePDM (8+ years) and Agile PLM Magma5.3 (CFD) 2+, Oracle ERP.

Data Analysis Tools Exposure:

Pythons, R Programming, Tableau, power BI

Environment Knowledge:

5s and kaizen and 6 sigma and lean manufacturing.

Hackathon Project:

Smart Grocery container (IOT Projects)

Other tools basic:

Adobe products (photoshop, illustrator & InDesign) and Simulation, Manufacturing (CAM), Autodesk products (Autodesk Fusion 360, FEA and DFMA basic knowledge in GD&T.

Awards:

• Spot award for best performance (2018/Altran)